Guide to the Richard Wright Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1934-1975; Series II; 7.5; (18 boxes)
  - PERSONAL CORRESPONDENCE
    - United States. Federal Security Agency, 1941-42 (Box 107, Folder 1647)
    - United States. Office of Facts and Figures, 1941-42 (Box 107, Folder 1648)
    - United States. Office of War Information, 1944-45 (Box 107, Folder 1649)
    - United States. Selective Service System, 1942-46 (Box 107, Folder 1650)
    - United States. Treasury Department, 1942-45 (Box 107, Folder 1651)
      See also: Julian Street, Box 106, folder 1637
    - United States. War Department, 1942, 1944 (Box 107, Folder 1652)
    - Unruh, Fritz and Friederike von, 1946-50 (Box 107, Folder 1653)
    - "V" general, 1942-59 (Box 107, Folder 1654)
    - Vaal, Hans de, 1951, 1953, n.d. (Box 107, Folder 1655)
    - Valentino Bompiano & C., 1948-52 (Box 107, Folder 1656)
    - Vallentin, Antonina, 1948, n.d. (Box 107, Folder 1657)
    - Vanguard Press, 1935-40 (Box 107, Folder 1658)
    - Van Vechten, Carl, 1939-46 (Box 107, Folder 1659)
      Includes photographs of Gertrude Stein and Alice B. Toklas
      See also: Walter White, Box 108, folder 1680
    - View, 1944-45 (Box 107, Folder 1660)
    - Viking Press, Inc., 1937-57 (Box 107, Folder 1661)
    - "W" general, 1935-73 (Box 107, Folder 1662-1663)
    - Wagner, Jean, 1957-58 (Box 107, Folder 1664)
    - Wahl, Maurice, 1947 Jul 10 (Box 107, Folder 1665)
    - Wakefield, Olive Lindsay, 1944-45 (Box 107, Folder 1666)
    - Walker, Margaret, 1937-41 (Box 107, Folder 1667)
    - Wallfisch, Erwin, 1950-51 (Box 107, Folder 1668)
    - Ward, Theodore, 1940 (Box 107, Folder 1669)
      Includes "We Ain't Comin!" (poem), "Comments on Native Son " (essay), "Plan of the Negro Playwrights Company", and "Budget for the production of Big White Fog"
    - Wauquier, René, 1946-54 (Box 107, Folder 1670)
    - Webb, Constance, 1942-63 (Box 107, Folder 1671)
    - Webster, David, 1950-51 (Box 107, Folder 1672)
    - Weichman, Myrtle L., 1947, 1957 (Box 107, Folder 1673)
    - Weigel, Henri, 1938-42 (Box 107, Folder 1674)
    - Welles, Orson, 1941, 1949, n.d. (Box 108, Folder 1675)
    - Wertham, Florence (Hesketh), 1941-47 (Box 108, Folder 1676)
    - Wertham, Frederick, 1941-54 (Box 108, Folder 1677)
    - Wescott, Glenway, 1944-46 (Box 108, Folder 1678)
    - West, C.H., 1944-47 (Box 108, Folder 1679)
    - White, Walter, 1941 (Box 108, Folder 1680)
      See also: National Association for the Advancement of Colored People, People, Box 102, folder 1489
    - Wickert, Erwin, 1951-60 (Box 108, Folder 1681)
    - Widén, Ruth, 1940-41 (Box 108, Folder 1682)
    - Wilkins, Roy
      See: National Association for the Advancement of Colored People, Box 102, folder 1489
    - Williams, Clayton E., 1948-53 (Box 108, Folder 1683)
    - Williams, Eric, 1945-55 (Box 108, Folder 1684)
    - Williams, Oscar, 1940 Jul 8 (Box 108, Folder 1685)
    - Willingham, Calder, 1947, 1955 (Box 108, Folder 1686)
    - Wilson, Edmund, 1959 Jul 2 (Box 108, Folder 1687)
    - Wiltwyck School for Boys, Inc., 1944-45 (Box 108, Folder 1688)
      See also: Box 139, folder 2029
    - Winser, Ethel Reid, 1940, n.d. (Box 108, Folder 1689)
    - Winslow, Henry F., Sr., 1959-60 (Box 108, Folder 1690)
    - Winter, Ella, 1942-[48?] (Box 108, Folder 1691)
    - Wirth, Louis and Mary, 1949-51 (Box 108, Folder 1692)
    - WIZO, 1955-56 (Box 108, Folder 1693)
    - Wolfe, Bernard, 1946-50 (Box 108, Folder 1694)
    - Wolfert, Vivian, 1945 (Box 108, Folder 1695)
    - Wood, Clement, 1942 Feb 28 (Box 108, Folder 1696)
    - Works Progress Administration
      See: Federal Theater Project, Box 97, folder 1330
      See: Negro History Project, Box 102, folder 1492
    - World Movement for World Federal Government
      See: David Webster, Box 107, folder 1672
    - World Publishing Company, 1942-60 (Box 108, Folder 1697)
    - Wright, Ellen and Julia, 1943-56, n.d. (Box 108, Folder 1698)
      Includes telegrams from Richard Wright
    - Writer's War Board, 1942-43 (Box 108, Folder 1699)
    - W.W. Norton and Company, 1936-37 (Box 108, Folder 1700)
    - Wylie, Philip
      See: Farrar & Rinehart and Writings, Box 97, folder 1325
      See: Blurb for Hodding Carter's The Winds of Fear, Box 8, folder 167
    - "Y" general, 1940-49 (Box 108, Folder 1701)
    - Yaddo, 1939, 1942 (Box 108, Folder 1702)
    - Yanover, Jules
    - Yergan, Max, 1938-52 (Box 108, Folder 1703)
    - Young Men's Hebrew Association, 1940-41 (Box 108, Folder 1704)
    - "Z" general, 1940-49 (Box 108, Folder 1705)
    - Zurit, Leonard, 1941-43 (Box 108, Folder 1706)
    - Unidentified - First names only, 1939-50 (Box 108, Folder 1707)
      Includes: Elise, Forbes, Frieda, George, Nora, Sol, Tony and Victor
    - Unidentified - General, 1938-59 (Box 108, Folder 1708)
  - THIRD-PARTY CORRESPONDENCE
    - Boal, P.L. and Jeanne M.
      - To Ellen Wright, 1951 (Box 109, Folder 1709)
    - Corbin, Mike
      - To Mike Gold, n.d. (Box 109, Folder 1710)
    - Délage, Sidney
      - To M. Leopold-Senghor, 1946 Apr 12 (Box 109, Folder 1711)
      - To M. Rabemananjara, 1946 Apr 12
    - Ford, James W.
      - To Carl Murphy, 1944 Apr (Box 109, Folder 1712)
    - Freund, Gisele
      - To Ellen Wright, n.d. (Box 109, Folder 1713)
    - Harper's Junior Bazaar
      - To Simone de Beauvoir, 1947 Apr 14 (Box 109, Folder 1714)
    - Henderson, Wilbur
      - To Mr. Corey, 1938 May 24 (Box 109, Folder 1715)
    - Henson, Francis A.
      - To Gertrude Stein, 1948 Apr 10 (Box 109, Folder 1716)
    - Jantuah, J.E.
      - To Kojo Botsio, 1959 Oct 13 (Box 109, Folder 1717)
    - Letters of acceptance for party
      Acceptances for party for Richard Wright addressed to Louise Adams Floyd from the following:
      - Leonard Abbott, 1940 Dec (Box 109, Folder 1718)
      - Bruce Bliven Harry Dana Lewis Gannett
      - Eileen Gillespie John Haynes Holmes Margaret Lamont Helen Porter Lowe Erich and Lotte Jacobi Reiss
      - Isabel Walker Soule Robertson Trowbridge Harry Weinberger Mr. & Mrs. Victor A. Yakhontoff Includes guest list
    - Letters of Recommendation for Richard Wright from T.C. Robinson
      - To Dr. Lovett, 1936 Feb 7 (Box 109, Folder 1719)
      - To Professor L. Martin, 1936 Feb 7
    - McCallum, C. E.
      - To Claude M. McCallum, 1943 Jul 3 (Box 109, Folder 1720)
      - To Coke Stevenson, 1944 Mar 27
    - Maniquet, L. de
      - [Note found in Richard Wright's copy of Black Boy ] to Ellen Wright, 1970[?] Jun 5 (Box 109, Folder 1720a)
    - Memorandum
      - To Lt. Col. Charles C. Dollard, et al., 1945 Oct 21 (Box 109, Folder 1721)
    - Salle, G.
      - To Ellen Wright, 1951 Jul 4 (Box 109, Folder 1722)
    - Sarrazac-Soulage, Robert
      - To Stéphane Strogoff, 1949 Feb 11 (Box 109, Folder 1723)
    - Simmons, John
      - To Marion Minus, n.d. (Box 109, Folder 1724)
    - Terkel, Studs
      - To Mr. Swan, 1964 Sep 2 (Box 109, Folder 1725)
        (Removed from audiotapes in Series III, Personal Papers)
    - Wright, Ellen
      - To Lucia Drudi, 1954 Jul 26 (Box 109, Folder 1726)
      - To Arthur Eckstein, 1947 May 6 (Box 109, Folder 1727)
    - ----, Violaine
      - To Ellen Wright, 1948 May 21 (Box 109, Folder 1728)
      - To Mary, [1948?] May 21
    - Unidentified
      - To Ollie, n.d. (Box 109, Folder 1729)
      - To Innes Rose, 1946 Dec 13
      - To Ellen Wright, 1946, n.d.
      - fragment of letter about Native Son, n.d.
  - FAN MAIL, GENERAL
    The following are general fan letters Wright. Letters about specific works are found in Series I, Writings.
    - "A" general, 1940-58 (Box 110, Folder 1730)
    - "B" general, 1940-60 (Box 110, Folder 1731)
    - "C" general, 1940-58 (Box 110, Folder 1732)
    - "D" general, 1940-60 (Box 110, Folder 1733)
    - "E" general, 1940-59 (Box 110, Folder 1734)
    - "F" general, 1941-60 (Box 110, Folder 1735)
    - "G" general, 1938-59 (Box 110, Folder 1736)
    - "H" general, 1934-60 (Box 110, Folder 1737)
    - "I-J-K" general, 1938-59 (Box 110, Folder 1738)
    - "L" general, 1938-59 (Box 110, Folder 1739)
    - "M" general, 1940-58 (Box 110, Folder 1740)
    - "N-O" general, 1940-59 (Box 110, Folder 1741)
    - "P-Q" general, 1938-59 (Box 110, Folder 1742)
    - "R" general, 1940-60 (Box 110, Folder 1743)
    - "S" general, 1938-59 (Box 110, Folder 1744)
    - "T-U-V" general, 1938-75 (Box 110, Folder 1745)
    - "W, Y-Z" general, 1940-75 (Box 110, Folder 1746)
    - Unidentified, 1942-60 (Box 110, Folder 1747)
- Personal Papers, 1927-1978; Series III; 3.5; (8 boxes)
  Series III, Personal Papers, is arranged alphabetically by type of material.
  - "L'Accueil de Paris" - statement of affairs, 1945 May 15 (Box 111, Folder 1748)
  - Addresses and telephone numbers for trip to Africa, 1959 (Box 111, Folder 1749)
  - Addresses notes, n.d. (Box 111, Folder 1750)
  - Advertisement for Harold R. Peat, Inc. representing Richard Wright as a speaker, [ca. 1945] (Box 111, Folder 1751)
  - Advertisement placed by Richard Wright seeking antique library cabinet, 1945 Aug 28 (Box 111, Folder 1752)
  - Advertisement placed by Richard Wright seeking lost valise, n.d. (Box 111, Folder 1753)
  - American Council on Race Relationships
    - Fundraising notes, 1945 (Box 111, Folder 1754)
    - Memo to Harry S. Truman, 1945 Jul 2
  - American Writers' Congress - schedule, n.d. (Box 111, Folder 1755)
  - Announcement of opening of Independent News Service [selling Negro publications] (Box 111, Folder 1756)
  - "Appel des Européens à l'Amerique," typescript corrected, n.d. (Box 111, Folder 1757)
  - Application for individual liquor permit, with permit [Canada], 1944-45 (Box 111, Folder 1758)
  - Application for Rustique Olivetti, 1956 Apr 3 (Box 111, Folder 1759)
  - Art and the Stars exhibit - announcement and catalog, 1942 (Box 111, Folder 1760)
  - ASCAP Articles of Association, with notes by Richard Wright, n.d. (Box 111, Folder 1761)
  - Audiotapes, 1960, 1964, n.d.
    - [collection of reel-to-reel tapes: 16 with lists of blues and jazz songs on covers (including "King Joe"), 4 containing various jazz, blues, folk songs and spirituals, 1 of Jelly Roll Morton, 3 containing classical music (Beethoven and Ravel), 1 recording of Richard Wright's speech at the American Church in Paris, November 8, 1960 (with duplicate made by Michel Fabre), 3-reel recording of Studs Terkel reading "The Man Who Lived Underground" on WFMT, with introduction by Michel Fabre, 1964 (with letter from Studs Terkel to Mr. Swan, 1964 Sep 23 photocopy - original filed in Third-Party Correspondence), and 1 "bad reel"]
      See: Oversize, Box 126, folder 1972
  - Audiotapes - Interview tapes, 1956-61
    [set of 7 tapes of interviews done with Richard Wright by RTF, Oct-Nov, 1960, 1 tape labeled: "Homage à Richard Wright", Nov, 1961 from Radiodiffusion de la France d'Outre-Mer including interview with Wright from Dec 16, 1959, 1 unidentified tape dated 6.2.56]
    See: Oversize, Box 126a, folder 1972a
  - Authors League Bulletin, 1947-48 (Box 111, Folder 1762)
  - Automobile accident report, 1947 Jul (Box 111, Folder 1763)
  - Bank account passbook and account cards, 1941-47 (Box 111, Folder 1764)
  - Baudelaire, Charles, "Elevation," typescript [with notes by Richard Wright[?]], n.d. (Box 111, Folder 1765)
  - Biographical article on Richard Wright, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 111, Folder 1766)
  - Biographical notes on Michel Bernheim, n.d. (Box 111, Folder 1767)
  - Blérancourt Seminar (Second) - handouts, 1958 (Box 111, Folder 1768)
  - Bread Loaf Writers' Conference Bulletin, 1945 (Box 111, Folder 1769)
  - Business cards and calling cards (Box 111, Folder 1770)
  - Camera [Contax 35mm in brown leather case - without lens], n.d.
    See: Oversize, Box 127, folder 1973
  - Camera instruction booklets, n.d. (Box 111, Folder 1770a)
  - Carnet di Venezia - program, 1951 Aug (Box 111, Folder 1771)
  - Certificate of literacy, 1938 Oct 15 (Box 111, Folder 1772)
  - "A Chaplain Speaks at Iwo Jima" [flyer], [1945] (Box 111, Folder 1773)
  - Clippings
    - Appearances by Richard Wright, 1936-57 (Box 111, Folder 1774)
    - Appearance by Richard Wright in North Carolina, 1940
      See: Oversize, Box 122, folder 1960
    - Articles compiled after Richard Wright's death [many concerning black literature], 1960-78 (Box 111, Folder 1775)
    - Authors' Guild, 1938-47 (Box 111, Folder 1776)
    - Awards and Prizes, 1938-42 (Box 111, Folder 1777)
    - Biography notices, n.d. (Box 112, Folder 1778)
    - Biographies of Richard Wright - reviews, 1964-78 (Box 112, Folder 1779)
    - Franco-American Fellowship, 1950-51 (Box 112, Folder 1780)
    - Garry Davis and Peace committee activities, 1948-49 (Box 112, Folder 1781)
    - General interest articles on Richard Wright, 1940-50 (Box 112, Folder 1782)
    - [intended as background for writings?], [1930s] (Box 112, Folder 1783)
    - Interviews and Profiles - in Dutch, Norwegian and Swedish, 1946-60 (Box 112, Folder 1784)
      See also: Oversize, Box 122, folder 1961
    - Interviews and Profiles - in English, 1940-56 (Box 112, Folder 1785)
      See also: Oversize, Box 122, folder 1962
    - Interviews and Profiles - in French, 1946-60 (Box 112, Folder 1786)
      See also: Oversize, Box 122, folder 1963
    - Interviews and Profiles - in German, 1946-60 (Box 112, Folder 1787)
    - Interviews and Profiles - in Italian, 1948-57 (Box 112, Folder 1788)
      See also: Oversize, Box 122, folder 1964
    - Interviews and Profiles - in Spanish and Portuguese, 1949-56 (Box 112, Folder 1789)
    - Johnson, James Weldon - Obituaries, 1938 Jun (Box 112, Folder 1790)
    - Lafargue Clinic / Frederick Wertham, 1946 (Box 112, Folder 1791)
    - Letters to the editor about Richard Wright, 1959, 1977 (Box 112, Folder 1792)
    - "A Liberal Dilemma" by Herbert Aptheker, New Masses [with notes by Richard Wright?], 1946 May 14 (Box 112, Folder 1793)
    - Literary Map of U.S.A. with reference to Native Son, 1941 Dec 3
      See: Oversize, Box 122, folder 1965
    - Literary references to Richard Wright - in English, 1940-60 (Box 112, Folder 1794)
    - Literary references to Richard Wright - in French, 1946-56 (Box 112, Folder 1795-1796)
    - Literary references to Richard Wright - in French, 1946-56 (Box 113, Folder 1797)
    - "Ni victimes, ni bourreaux" series by Albert Camus, 1946 Nov (Box 113, Folder 1798)
    - Obituaries of Richard Wright - in Dutch, English, French and German, 1960-61 (Box 113, Folder 1799)
    - Photographs and pictures of Richard Wright, 1940-59 (Box 113, Folder 1800)
    - Projects involving Richard Wright, 1934-56 (Box 113, Folder 1801)
      See also: Oversize, Box 122, folder 1966
    - Quotations from Wright, 1942-54 (Box 113, Folder 1802)
    - Social references to Richard Wright, 1936-59 (Box 113, Folder 1803)
    - 13 Against the Odds by Edwin R. Embree [containing biography of Richard Wright] - reviews, 1944 (Box 113, Folder 1804)
    - "Your History" cartoon featuring Richard Wright, 1957 Mar 30 (Box 113, Folder 1805)
    - Various subjects - including racial issues, black celebrities and friends of Richard Wright, 1927-60 (Box 113, Folder 1806)
      [Includes complete issues of: Daily Mail 1948 Sep 16 Daily Worker 1946 Feb 11 New York Herald Tribune 1948 Sep 16 New York Times 1946 Apr 22 P.M. Magazine 1941 Feb 17, 1943 Feb 7 & Jun 20 and 1944 Jul 28]
  - Comments on text about African and slave musicians, typescript carbon (Box 113, Folder 1807)
  - "Committee Report to the Tenants League of 89-105 Lefferts Place", n.d. (Box 113, Folder 1807a)
  - Communist Party Nominating Petition for Councilman, 1943 (Box 113, Folder 1808)
  - Conseil de Solidarité Garry Davis - notes, n.d. (Box 113, Folder 1809)
  - Crane, Hart, "To Brooklyn Bridge," typescript [with notes by Richard Wright?], n.d. (Box 113, Folder 1810)
  - Customs documents, 1949-50 (Box 113, Folder 1811)
  - Diary, 1945 (Box 113, Folder 1812)
  - Documents for Bandung Conference, 1955 (Box 113, Folder 1813)
  - Drawings by Julia Wright, 1945
    See: Oversize, Box 122, folder 1967
  - Driver's licenses and receipt for driving lessons, 1947-51 (Box 113, Folder 1814)
  - Engagement calendars, 1941-45, 1948 (Box 114, Folder 1815-1817)
  - [on Epiphanism - fragment intended to be signed by Henri Perruchet, Michel Ragon, Gaston Criel, et al.], typescript carbon (Box 115, Folder 1818)
  - Equity of Chicago Artists - draft of constitution, n.d. (Box 115, Folder 1819)
  - Eugene Field Society - certificate of honorary membership, 1940 May 28 (Box 115, Folder 1820)
  - "Excerpts from reviews of Fire in Summer " [by Robert Ramsey], flyer, 1942 (Box 115, Folder 1821)
  - Eyeglasses [4 pair with cases, 9 pair loose and one pair lenses]
    See: Oversize, Box 128, folders 1974-1975
  - Film - Screen test for Native Son: Richard Wright as Bigger Thomas in 3 scenes, 2 takes each, running time approximately 7-1/2 minutes, 1948 (Box 115, Folder 1821a)
    See: Oversize, Box 140, folder 2036
  - Film - documents accompanying original reels of screen test, 1948 (Box 115, Folder 1821b)
  - Financial notes - for taxes, expenses, etc. [including notes on a letter from Mrs. Otto Madlener - 1945], [ca. 1940s] (Box 115, Folder 1822)
  - Franco-American Fellowship
    - Aims of the Organization - circular, n.d. (Box 115, Folder 1823)
    - Clippings [included with records], n.d. (Box 115, Folder 1824)
    - Constitution and rules - drafts and final versions, [1950-51] (Box 115, Folder 1825)
    - Correspondence, 1950-52 (Box 115, Folder 1826)
      [Includes: Roger Baldwin, Daniel Guérin, Margaret McLelland and Maurice Raphäel]
    - Employment applications, [1950-51] (Box 115, Folder 1827)
    - Financial and legal documents, 1951 (Box 115, Folder 1828-1829)
    - Invitations and envelopes, 1950 (Box 115, Folder 1830)
    - Membership applications, 1950-51 (Box 115, Folder 1831)
    - Membership cards for Minto Cato, Eric Thomas and Richard Wright, 1951 May (Box 115, Folder 1832)
    - Membership lists, [1950-51] (Box 115, Folder 1833)
    - Minutes and reports, 1950-51 (Box 115, Folder 1834-1835)
    - Notebook with police imprimatur, 1951 Nov 7 (Box 115, Folder 1836)
    - Press conference documents on Margaret McLelland and the American Hospital, 1951 (Box 115, Folder 1837)
      [Includes letter from Elizabeth Ann Edwards to Richard Wright]
    - Printed material, 1950-51 (Box 115, Folder 1838)
    - Schedule for symposium on race relations [fragment], n.d. (Box 115, Folder 1839)
    - "What is the Franco-American Fellowship?" circular, n.d. (Box 115, Folder 1840)
    - World Council for the People's World Convention - brochure, n.d. (Box 115, Folder 1841)
  - French lessons - notes, n.d. (Box 116, Folder 1842-1847)
  - Gran Premio Internazionale Saint Vincente - brochure, 1950 (Box 116, Folder 1848)
  - Identification and membership cards, 1933-57 (Box 116, Folder 1849)
  - Illustrations of postures for the kavain, n.d. (Box 116, Folder 1850)
  - Income tax document - State of New York, 1942 Mar 19 (Box 116, Folder 1851)
  - [Information on birth control], typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 116, Folder 1852)
  - Insignia "Richard Wright" in metal, n.d. (Box 116, Folder 1853)
  - Interview tapes
    See: Audiotapes - Interview tapes, Box 111, folder 1762
  - Interview with Richard Wright by Betty Wells, broadcast by KRNT, Des Moines, Iowa (16" audiodisc), 1945 Nov 15
    See: Oversize, Box 129a, folder 1975a
  - Interview with Richard Wright published in French school newspaper [with cover letter], 1959 May (Box 116, Folder 1854)
  - Invitations and announcements
    - Appearances by Richard Wright, 1936-56 (Box 117, Folder 1855)
      See also: Oversize, Box 122, folder 1968
    - Events concerning Richard Wright, 1939-46 (Box 117, Folder 1856)
    - Other events, 1936-48 (Box 117, Folder 1857)
  - John Reed Club
    - Data blank for American Art Annual, 1935 (Box 117, Folder 1858)
    - List of Resolutions and Preamble to Constitutions of Individual Clubs
    - Stationery for Left Front [one sheet], n.d. (Box 117, Folder 1859)
  - Journals, 1945, 1947 (Box 117, Folder 1860-1861)
  - Kumba Tam: ein Afrika Beitrag, 1947 Summer (Box 117, Folder 1862)
  - Leather wallet embossed with name "Richard Wright", including two Spanish 25 peseta coins, n.d. (Box 117, Folder 1863)
  - Library cards, 1940-58 (Box 117, Folder 1864)
  - Lists of and notes about photographic equipment (Box 117, Folder 1865)
  - List of movie theaters in Latin America, n.d. (Box 117, Folder 1866)
  - List of names on "Wall of Fame" at World Fair (New York), [1940] (Box 117, Folder 1867)
  - List of names of "Negro Colleges" and "Leading Negro Newspapers", [1944] (Box 117, Folder 1868)
  - List of photographs of Richard Wright and family (Box 117, Folder 1869)
  - List of "Wright invitations", n.d. (Box 117, Folder 1870)
  - Lottery ticket from Spain, 1954 Aug 25 (Box 117, Folder 1871)
  - Map of England [torn] (Box 117, Folder 1871a)
  - Map of Huckleberry Hill and environs (Box 117, Folder 1872)
  - Mock Newspaper, The Chicago View, with headline: "Dick Wright Noted Author Off to N.Y.", n.d.
    See: Oversize, Box 122, folder 1968
  - Die Nieuwe Stem [periodical], 1965 Jan (Box 117, Folder 1873)
  - Notes on bank account statement - including Haiku, holograph, 1960 (Box 117, Folder 1874)
  - Notes on locales in Paris, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 117, Folder 1875)
  - Notes - "to do" lists etc., mostly holograph, [ca. 1940s-50s] (Box 117, Folder 1876)
  - Notice of replevin and sale against Cynthia Pennell by Richard Wright, 1947 Jan 2 (Box 117, Folder 1877)
  - Notice of termination of employment from Federal Writers Project, 1939 May 15 (Box 117, Folder 1878)
  - Offprint of Der Speigel magazine cover ("Die Kral-verwandtschaften"), 1956 Oct 24 (Box 117, Folder 1879)
  - Parliamentary Debates - House of Commons Official Report, 1958 Nov 19-20 (Box 117, Folder 1880)
    [regarding Wright's request to immigrate to the United Kingdom]
  - Passenger lists (ships), 1940-55 (Box 117, Folder 1881)
  - Passports and visas, 1950, 1957 (Box 117, Folder 1882)
  - Photographic scrapbook from Second Blérancourt Seminar, 1958 May (Box 118, Folder 1883)
  - Photographs [22 prints], n.d. (Box 118, Folder 1884)
    Includes: Baby Lois
    - Optical illusion of face, n.d.
    - Richard Wright in pose, by Kurt Waldheim, n.d.
    - Richard Wright casual snapshot, 1936
    - Richard Wright in beret, n.d.
    - Richard Wright with cat [2 different prints], n.d.
    - Richard Wright with photographer in Chicago, 1940 Mar
    - Richard Wright portrait poses [5 prints including 1 sheet of 4 poses], n.d.
    - Richard Wright speaking in New York, 1940 Mar 11
    - Richard Wright speaking at the University of North Carolina, 1940 Jul
    - Richard Wright speaking at the Golden Gate Ballroom, New York, 1940
    - Richard Wright speaking at the Good Shepherd Church, Chicago [3 poses], 1940 Jun
    - Richard Wright with unidentified woman [2 different prints], n.d.
    - Richard Wright with unidentified man, n.d.
  - Postcard of Quebec [blank] with bus schedule, n.d. (Box 118, Folder 1885)
  - Postcard with photograph of Richard Wright, [1945] (Box 118, Folder 1886)
  - Posters with poems: "The Exodus" and "Take Dad's Advice and Don't be a Fool!" by A. Namderloc
    See: Oversize, Box 122, folder 1968a
  - Practice for the Army Test booklet with notes, 1942 (Box 118, Folder 1886a)
  - Prescriptions, 1949, n.d. (Box 118, Folder 1887)
  - Press badge for Bandung Conference, 1955 (Box 118, Folder 1888)
  - Press comment about Walk Hard by Abram Hill, circular, 1944 Dec (Box 118, Folder 1889)
  - Promissory notes, 1947 (Box 118, Folder 1890)
  - Proposal for establishing a journal for English and French speaking blacks (Box 118, Folder 1891)
  - "Questionnaire Marcel Proust à Monsieur Richard Wright" [blank], n.d. (Box 118, Folder 1892)